http://www.blindness.org/privacy-policy

Usher Syndrome
X-Linked Retinoschisis (XLRS)
Access to Retinal Disease Eye Tissue
Virtual Workshop on Inflammation in Viral Gene Therapy of the Retina
Privacy Policy
The Foundation Fighting Blindness supports full knowledge and disclosure of our privacy policy. This statement discloses the privacy practices for the Foundation Fighting Blindness's Web site. This policy addresses...
OUR COMMITMENT TO PRIVACY
WHAT INFORMATION IS COLLECTED
HOW INFORMATION IS USED
WITH WHOM THE INFORMATION MAY BE SHARED
RECEIVING E-MAIL AND DIRECT MAIL
HOW TO UPDATE, CHANGE, OR DELETE YOUR INFORMATION
RIGHT TO OPT-OUT
OUR COMMITMENT TO DATA SECURITY
OUR COMMITMENT TO CHILDREN'S PRIVACY
GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (GDPR) - EUROPEAN REPRESENTATIVE
HOW TO CONTACT US
OUR COMMITMENT TO PRIVACY
Your privacy is very important to us. The Foundation Fighting Blindness has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our respect for our users' personal privacy. The following provides our information gathering, security and disclosure practices for this Web site, www.FightingBlindness.org and our subsidiary, www.VisionWalk.org, which are owned and operated by the Foundation Fighting Blindness. We may change this policy at any time by posting a new privacy policy at this location. Please be sure to check this page periodically for changes.
Procedures are in place to help ensure the safety and security of information collected through our Web site. This includes, but is not limited to, appropriate Internet and server (physical) security, application design and managerial practices and principles required by the Foundation Fighting Blindness. For more information, please review Our Commitment To Data Security.
This Web site may contain links to other Web sites, such as other organizations providing services or products to visually impaired people, sponsors, advertisers, and business partners. The Foundation Fighting Blindness is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites to which it links, or any site that provides a link to www.FightingtBlindness.org.
Back to top
WHAT INFORMATION IS COLLECTED
Personal Information
We only collect personally identifiable information you voluntarily provide in order to obtain our customized information and services. Personally identifiable information includes, but is not limited to, first and last name, physical address, e-mail address, phone number, social security number, birth date, credit card information and any other information that itself identifies or when tied to the above information, may identify you as a specific individual. All of the information you provide us is treated as confidential by us. This information is used specifically by the Foundation Fighting Blindness to provide information and/or services to our constituents. Under no circumstance is personal information shared with any other source, or third party, that is not required to deliver the products/services requested by the user, or by law. We do not sell or exchange our constituents' personal information.
On some pages, you can submit information about other people. For example, if you make a donation online and want to send a tribute card to the honoree, you will need to submit the recipient's address.
Your confidential information is stored by the Foundation Fighting Blindness and is maintained in a highly secure environment, not available to the general public, which includes, but is not limited to, Internet and physical security, as well as strict managerial policies and procedures.
Aggregate/ Non Identifying Information
When you visit our site, we collect some basic and anonymous information about your computer, including, but not limited to:
We use information collected about your computer and/or browser system to perform routine Web site maintenance and to generate aggregate Web site traffic reports so we can develop site content and features of value to you.
Policy on Cookies
A cookie is a small data file that certain Web sites place on a users hard drive when a user visits that site. Cookie files often contain information such as a user ID, which the site uses to track pages of the Web site, visited by the user.
The only personal information a cookie can contain is information that the user supplies.
A user can always refuse cookies by turning them off in the users browser. Cookies do not need to be turned on to use the Foundation Fighting Blindness site.
The Foundation Fighting Blindness may use cookies to:
Track users on database pages, to determine whether they are a new user or a repeat visitor.
Compile detailed site usage statistics and generate reports by selecting from a range of variables.
Determine when a user links to another site by first visiting www.FightingBlindness.org.
The Foundation Fighting Blindness is not responsible for the cookie policies at other sites that our Web site links to, or sites that link to our Web site.
Back to top
HOW INFORMATION IS USED
Registration Forms -Personal Information
We will use customer contact information provided by users on their registration forms to send the user information, newsletters, and notifications about the Foundation Fighting Blindness's services and how you may support the Foundation.
Non-personally identifying or aggregate information
The Foundation Fighting Blindness may use non-personally identifying information, such a user's IP address, operating system, browser type, domain names and what Web site the user came from, to help diagnose problems with our server, perform routine Web site maintenance, administer our Web site, and to generate aggregate Web site traffic reports so we can develop site content and features of value to you.
Back to top
WITH WHOM THE INFORMATION MAY BE SHARED
Third-Party Contractors
We have agreements with third-party contractors, who assist in providing information and services associated to this site. These companies may have access to required personal information in order to fulfill an information request by the user. These relationships are standard and are required to provide this information and services. Third-party contractors will not store or share personal information on our registrant.
In all cases, FFB requires every third-party contractor to sign a privacy agreement so that they treat your information as confidential as we do. All third-party contractors are required to follow confidentiality policies as defined by the Foundation Fighting Blindness, as well as our Commitment To Data Security.
Partnerships
The Foundation Fighting Blindness has established and is continuing to develop online and offline "partnerships" with both private and public corporations and organizations for the purpose of improving and promoting our information, services, events and charitable fundraising activities. The Foundation Fighting Blindness may from time to time build co-branded sites, co-branded pages, or provide unique services or offers through such partnerships. The Foundation Fighting Blindness will not share any personally identifiable user information with our partners without the user's express permission.
Back to top
HOW TO UPDATE, CHANGE, OR DELETE YOUR INFORMATION
Updating Your Profile
The Foundation Fighting Blindness users may update, correct, or change their profiles, which are accessible at www.FightingBlindness.org. Users can change their information at any time, by selecting "Edit Registration." Users are required to enter in their Login ID and password before changes to their record are permitted. Users who have questions about this process can contact the Foundation Fighting Blindness by e-mail: info@FightingBlindness.org .
The Foundation Fighting Blindness reserves the right to maintain email addresses, to notify users of news, events, newsletters and changes to FFB services. By choosing to "unsubscribe" in future emails, restrictions on email usage will be followed.
Back to top
RIGHT TO OPT-OUT
You have the right to "opt-out" of certain of our uses of your Personal Information. For example, at the time you are requested to provide Personal Information on this Web Site and/or through our Services, you may have the opportunity to elect to, or not to: (1) receive promotional correspondence from Foundation Fighting Bindness or (2) have your Personal Information shared with other companies or individuals. You may also make this request by sending an e-mail to info@fightingblindness.org. In this e-mail please identify which Foundation Fighting Blindness Web site or Service you are referring to (or all of them) and say whether (i) you would like to opt-out of receiving promotional correspondence (including, for example, e-mail offers) in general, or just via e-mail, postal mail, short message service, instant messaging and/or by phone, (ii) you would like to opt-out of certain of Foundation Fighting Bindness' e-newsletters or correspondence, and if so which ones, and/or (iii) you would like to opt-out of having your Personal Information shared with other companies or individuals. You may also opt-out of Foundation Fighting Blindness e-mails by clicking on an opt-out link within the promotional correspondence you receive, sending an email to info@fightingblindness.org or opt-out of Foundation Fighting Blindness promotional email or SMS correspondence or Premium SMS Services by texting "STOP" to the shortcode provided on the Web Site for the particular Service. Please understand that if you opt-out of receiving promotional e-mails or SMS from Foundation Fighting Blindness, we may still contact you by e-mail or SMS in connection with your account with us or to provide you with important information about Foundation Fighting Blindness or this Web Site or the Services. Also, a request to have us stop sharing your Personal Information with other companies or individuals will only apply as of the date of the request, and Foundation Fighting Blindness will not be responsible for any communications that you may receive from companies or individuals that received your Personal Information prior to such request. In these cases, please contact that company or individual directly.
OUR COMMITMENT TO DATA SECURITY
Information provided by a user through this site shall not be used for any purpose other than that which is clearly indicated by the Web site. Reasonable steps, to ensure information provided is kept secure and confidential, are provided below:
Physical
Appropriate physical security measures are followed by the Foundation Fighting Blindness to ensure the protection and safety of our servers. In part, this includes adequate building, server room, server, firewall and server configuration. FFB's policies and procedures for maintaining physical security are updated as needed, or required as changes in security measures can be effectively and reasonably utilized by the company.
Internet
This site has reasonable security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of information under our control. When a user places an order with FFB online, personal information and credit card information are scrambled using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology before being sent over the Internet. This technology is intended to prevent user information from being stolen or intercepted while being transferred through cyberspace. When we receive an order, it is kept encrypted until it is processed. Credit card information is then erased from our Web site. No credit card information is stored within our database.
Managerial
The Foundation Fighting Blindness takes numerous precautions to ensure the confidentiality of information provided by our customers. Strict managerial practices are followed to prevent misuse of information, or the use of information for any reason that is not necessary to perform and deliver products and services through our Web site.
FFB's privacy principles include:
A requirement of all third-party contractors to sign a privacy and confidentiality agreement. No information may be used by a third-party, for any reason, except to fulfill an information service or donation requested by you through the Foundation Fighting Blindness Web site; or to investigate a claim against the third-party.
At any time, an FFB constituent may choose to "unsubscribe" of our Web site.
The Foundation Fighting Blindness may disclose information provided by a user, if required by law or to investigate a claim against the company.
FFB will conduct managerial, Internet and physical security audits to ensure proper privacy procedures are followed.
Back to top
OUR COMMITMENT TO CHILDREN'S PRIVACY
Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13.
Back to top
GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (GDPR) - EUROPEAN REPRESENTATIVE
Pursuant to Article 27 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), The Foundation Fighting Blindness, Inc., has appointed European Data Protection Office (EDPO) as its GDPR representative in the EU. You can contact EDPO regarding matters pertaining to the GDPR by:
- Using EDPO’s online request form at https://edpo.com/gdpr-data-request/ - Writing to EDPO at Avenue Huart Hamoir 71, 1030 Brussels, Belgium
Back to top
HOW TO CONTACT US
The Foundation Fighting Blindness welcomes your feedback about this privacy statement and about the Foundation Fighting Blindness' services and products.
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact:
Constituent Services CoordinatorFoundation Fighting Blindness6925 Oakland Mills Road, #701Columbia, MD 21045
Email: info@FightingBlindness.orgToll Free: (800) 683-5555TDD: (800) 683-5551Local: (410) 423-0600Local TDD: (410) 363-7139
Back to top
Foundation Fighting Blindness homepage
The urgent mission of the Foundation Fighting Blindness is to drive the research that will provide preventions, treatments and cures for people affected by retinitis pigmentosa, age-related macular degeneration, Usher syndrome and the entire spectrum of retinal degenerative diseases. The Foundation is a beacon for those affected by these blinding diseases. Join the fight and help us accelerate our mission.
Welcome to the Foundation site — supported in partnership with Genentech, A Member of the Roche Group.
Better Business Bureau Accredited Charity
FFB meets all 20 Better Business Bureau Charity Standards.
Sign Up to Receive Updates and Communications from the Foundation!
Sign Up
Get in Touch
Facebook.
Twitter.
YouTube.
Instagram.
Foundation Fighting Blindness
Phone:
(800) 683-5555
6925 Oakland Mills Road, #701,
Columbia,
MD
21045.
Donations can be mailed directly to:
Foundation Fighting Blindness, P.O. Box 45740, Baltimore, MD 21297-5740
Retinal Education
Information for Newly Diagnosed
An Eye on Education Video Series
Achromatopsia
Bardet-Biedl Syndrome
Best Disease
Choroideremia
Leber Congenital Amaurosis
Macular Degeneration
Retinitis Pigmentosa
Refsum Disease
Stargardt Disease
Usher Syndrome
X-Linked Retinoschisis (XLRS)
Other Retinal Conditions
Glossary
Stories & Resources
Genetic Testing
Research
Get Involved
Ways to Give
Shop Fighting Blindness
Site Map
© 2020 Foundation Fighting Blindness, All Rights Reserved. The Foundation Fighting Blindness is a qualified 501(c)(3) non-profit organization and all donations are tax deductible. EIN 23-7135845.
